<Word>
<Text>يكذب</Text>
<Status>NEW</Status>
<Root>To lie, say what is not a fact, lie to falsely invent, tell lies about or against, fabricate a lie, relate a lie, say a falsehood, be wrong, be cut off, deceive, disappoint the expectation of.</Root>
<Transliteration>yakazaibu</Transliteration>
<MeaningSimple>To deny, to treat as a liar. To lie.</MeaningSimple>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>كَذَبَ  aor.  يَكْذِبُ inf. noun  كَذِبًا and  كِذْبًا and كِذَّابًا .  كَذَبَ   : He lied; he uttered a falsehood; he said what was untrue; he gave an untrue account of a thing whether intentionally or unintentionally; he committed a mistake or error.</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(9:77:3:5) : Because they lied.</Example>
		<Example>Token(39:33:5:7) : Who lies against God.</Example>
	</Meaning>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>كَذَبَ   also means he found his hopes to be false or vain. كَذَبَ الْحَرُّ  : The heat abated. كَذَبَتْكَ عَيْنُكَ  : Thine eye showed thee what had no reality. كَذَبَ الْاَمْرَ  : He imagined the thing contrary to its real state.</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(53:12:1:2)  : The heart (of the Prophet) was not untrue to what he saw (53:12).</Example>
		<Example>كَذَبَتْهُ نَفْسُهٗ  : His soul made him desire things and conceive hopes that could scarcely come to pass.</Example>
	</Meaning>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>كُذِبَ  : He was told a lie, a falsehood. To be told a lie.</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(12:111:2:5) : They (the disbelievers) thought that they had been told lies (12:111).</Example>
	</Meaning>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>كَذَّبَهٗ  : He pronounced him to be a liar; he ascribed lying to him; he gave him the lie; he treated him as a liar.</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(26:118:3:5) : My people has treated me as a liar (26:118).</Example>
		<Example>كَذَّبَ اِالْاَمْرِ  : He rejected, denied, disbelieved in the thing.Token(10:96:2:3)  :  They rejected the Signs of Allah (10:96).</Example>
		<Example>كِذَّابًا  inf.Token(78:29:1:2) noun from كَذِب</Example>
		<Example>تَكْذِيْبٌ  (inf. Token(85:20:2:5) noun from كَذَّبَ   اَكْذَبَهٗ : He found him a liar; he made manifest or proved his lying. كَاذِبٌ  : Act. part.</Example>
		<Example>Token(11:94:13:15) كَذِبَ</Example>
		<Example>Token(56: 3:2:3)  كَاذِبَةٌ  feminine of  كَاذِبٌ</Example>
		<Example>كَاذِبِيْنَ  and  كَاذِبُوْنَ plural. مُكَذِّبُوْنَ  : Act. part. From كَذَّبَ  .  مَكْذُوْبٌ  (lie) : Pass. part. Token(11:66:9:11)  اَكْذَبُ Token(54:26:6:9)</Example>
	</Meaning>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>كَذَّابٌ  : Intensive form of  كَاذِبٌ meaning, a great liar كَذْبٌ   : A lie; a falsehood; a fiction; a fable; false.   مَكْذُوْبٌ  اَلْكِذْبُ  is of five kinds: (a) The relator altering what he hears or his relating as from others what he does not know; (b) The saying what resembles a lie, not meaning anything but the truth; (c) The saying what is untrue by mistake or unintentionally; (d) The finding one's hopes vain or false (e) The act of instigating.</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(3:76:31:36)</Example>
		<Example>Token(12:19:1:5): With false blood (12:19).</Example>
	</Meaning>
</Word>
