 <Word>
<Text>يكتب</Text>
<Status>NEW</Status>
<Root>To write, to dictate. To prescribe, appoint or ordain. To judge, pass sentence. Decreed. To draw, to bring together. Collected, conjoined  or  bound, to sewed. What is written (e.g. of law). Mode or manner of writing, Book, bookseller, a thing in which or on which one writes, record or register. A writ, revealed scripture. A a writer, scribe or secretary. An army or military force, troop.</Root>
<Transliteration>yaktaba</Transliteration>
<MeaningSimple>To write. He writes.</MeaningSimple>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>كَتَبَ aor.  يَكْتُبُ inf. noun كِتَابًا : He wrote; he was a writer, or scribe and a learned man وَلْيَكْتُبْ بَّيْنَكُمْ</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(2:283:8:9) Let him write in your presence.  كَاتِبٌ</Example>
		<Example>Token(7:158:4:6)  كَاتِبُوْنَ  and  كَاتِبِيْنَ (plural of كَاتِبٌ)</Example>
		<Example>مَكْتُوْبٌ  (passive part).</Example>
		<Example>Token(25:6:4:5) اِكْتَتَبَهَا  He has got them written down (25:6).</Example>
	</Meaning>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>كَتَبَ To prescribe. Ordain. To appoint. Divine prescript, appointment or ordinance. Judgement or sentence; decree or predestination.</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(7:158:4:6) He (God) prescribed, appointed or ordained and made obligatory.</Example>
		<Example>Token(2:184:4:5)  Fasting is prescribed as incumbent upon you (2:184).</Example>
		<Example>Token(4:104:6:8) Prayer is enjoined on the believers to be performed at fixed hours (4:104).</Example>
		<Example>Token(4:25:3:4) Enjoined upon you by God (4:25).</Example>
	</Meaning>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>كَتَابَ عَنْهُ  : He wrote what he had heard from him. كَاتَبَهٗ . A contract, a contract of marriage</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(24:34:4:5) noun مُكَاتَبَةٌ He (a slave) made a written (or other) contract with him (his master) that he should pay a certain sum as the price of himself and on the payment thereof be free, also he (master) made such a contract with the slave (24:34).</Example>
	</Meaning>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>كِتَابٌ  A book; a record; a revealed scripture; judgement or sentence; decree or predestination; destiny; fate.</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(12:2:4:5)  Clear book (12:2).</Example>
		<Example>Token(9:36:17:19)  In the Book of Allah; by Allah's ordinance (9:36).</Example>
	</Meaning>
	<Meaning>
		<Definition>A record; a revealed scripture; contract of marriage; destiny; fate.</Definition>
		<Reference>Ghulam Farid</Reference>
		<Example>Token(23:63:1:2)  With Us is a record (23:63).</Example>
		<Example>Token(43:5:3:4)  In the mother of the Book or the original of the Book; the source of Decrees(43:5).</Example>
		<Example>Token(98:4:1:2)  كُتُبٌ  plural of  كِتَابٌ .</Example>
	</Meaning>
</Word>